# **Terence Mark Hackett**

19 Talbotville Road, Broadgreen, Liverpool L13 4BH

Telephone: 0151 291 5238 (Home); 07766 110 250 (Mobile)

Email: Terry.hackett@sky.com

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I started my working career as a Vehicle Technician, moved on to Workshop Control then Manager and finally Senior Management. I found this experience has given me a valuable more rounded approach to the industry from the knowledge I have gained.

I am an Aftersales Manager currently with Inchcape PLC based in Liverpool, at present I manage a large, state of the art Workshop with 38 members of staff.

I consider myself a very confidant, outgoing person and this shows in my management style. I pride myself on giving 110% on every challenge that I face and in the current climate I find myself faced with many challenges on a daily basis.

My style of management incorporates many skills that I have learnt from my time in the industry. Although most of my time has been spent in Aftersales, I made sure I attended all Aftersales / Management training courses and meetings to familiarise myself with as much knowledge of the industry as I could.

I consider myself a very approachable manager; a people person keen to try out new ideas and modern technology; I believe in management though support and motivation rather than a fear and "shout" management style. I also pride myself on a firm but fair approach and I find this then gains the respect of my colleagues, enabling me to get the best out of them.

I firmly believe in the service profit chain and incorporate this in my style of management:

Happy Staff = Happy Customers=££'s

### **EDUCATION AND QUALIFICATIONS**

City & Guilds: City & Guilds – motor vehicle engineering – Riversdale College (1985-1989)

5 CSEs grade 1: Including English & Mathematics (1985) St Frances Xavier RC School, Liverpool

#### **KEY I.T. SKILLS**

- · Basic Microsoft, Internet & Email
- Kerridge

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

2008 - Present Site Aftersales Director - Mercedes Benz of Liverpool

I started off in servicing / repairing just 20 vehicles with 15 staff producing around 1350 hours per month, this produced around £65,000 to £100,000 net profit per month.

I increased this site over a period of time to what it is now to 38 staff repairing over c80 vehicles/day and 2500 to 3000 hours/month producing around £225,000 to £270,000 excluding parts sales. But turning over around £350,000 including parts sales.

Although my workshop runs around 125% efficient I am looking to implement a shift system of 12 hour days 6 days a week to enable us to extend the capacity and throughput but even with this we need to expand. At present I am working on a business plan to extend our facility by 25%.

At Inchcape I follow a strict process driven shop, I forecast our end of month figures once a week and check our figures and debts on a daily basis. We have team meetings and production meetings every day in order to ensure we achieve our daily targets

### 2006 - 2008 Service Manager – Mercedes Benz of Warrington

When I started, I was told that this was a department with no leadership. The manufacturer refused to come to the site as it was in disarray; sales and customer satisfaction was the lowest in the country. I restructured the department with the introduction of a night shift, due to site restrictions and lack of space; the only way to meet customer demand was to introduce this shift. The department went from strength to strength with a rise in staff morale, the increase in profitability, but more importantly the massive increase in customer satisfaction from one of the lowest to one of the highest in the 149 dealers at the time.

### 2004 - 2006 General Manager – Mercedes Benz of Wirral

I resolved the issues of the Aftersales department and it was making a profit. Sales were still struggling but I felt I had made a lot of improvements to the site. It underwent a major site refurbishment and we managed to keep the site functional throughout. The contractor on site implemented all of my ideas and we made best use of the space available. The refurbishment was a success and the staff morale was very high on the site and I felt this was due to the rapport I had with them I moved because I felt I had done as much as I could and wanted another challenge.

### 2002 - 2004 Prep Centre Manager – Roadrange Mercedes Benz

Roadrange had decided to try a different approach to new and used car preparation and I was chosen to manage the site. I set the site up and put procedures in place and the whole outfit was running successfully. We managed throughput of 300 plus cars a month for all of the Roadrange dealerships in the North West of England. Only left the post when approached to become General Manager at the Wirral dealership.

## 2001 - 2002 Service Manager – Roadrange Wirral

The Aftersales department was making a loss and I was given the task of turning the department into a profit making centre and raising staff morale. Within three months the site had broken even and begun to make a profit. I made a lot of staff changes and brought in staff from other Roadrange dealerships; using the knowledge and experience I gleaned at Liverpool to make Wirral one of the best Aftersales departments in the group. It was with some regret I handed the reigns over to my replacement.

# 1999 - 2001 Aftersales Controller – Roadrange Liverpool

It was whilst doing this job I realised my vocation. I loved it. I and the other Aftersales controller had implemented changes to Liverpool, which made it run like clockwork. The staff were working to their full potential and earning the company a tidy profit. The other Aftersales controller moved on to another post and I was left in charge. Building up a good rapport with the staff (to the extent that some have followed me around the company).

### 1998 - 1999 Workshop Foreman – Roadrange Liverpool

Running workshop employing fifteen technicians and three apprentices

### 1997 - 1998 Quality Controller – Roadrange Liverpool

Controlling up to 50% of work being carried out in the workshop

# 1991 - 1997 Motor Vehicle Technician – Roadrange Liverpool

Technician working on Mercedes Benz. Qualified MOT tester.

# 1985 - 1991 Motor Vehicle Technician – Mayfield Garage SAAB

Time served apprentice becoming full motor vehicle technician for SAAB

PERSONAL DETAILS

**Driving Licence:** Full UK

**Health:** Excellent; non-smoker

Interests include: Football, Travel, Cycling, Walking and Reading.

.

## **References Available On Request**